HENRY ZIMMERMAN

hgz1374@gmail.com · github.com/hgzimmerman · 847-287-1920

PROFILE

Dedicated Software Engineer specializing in finding and defining problems and leading the charge to solve them. Interested in emerging ideas such as utilizing Rust within the web development domain. Available for full-time employment starting July 2018. Competencies in:

- Fullstack Web Development
- Rust
- Linear and Agile Software Development
- · Small team development
- Designing for long-term maintenance
- · Security in distributed systems

EDUCATION

BS Software Engineering Rochester Institute of Technology

May 2019

RELEVANT EXPERIENCE

Software Engineer (Co-Op) Ocient

Aug 2016 - Jan 2017 | May 2017 - Aug 2017

DB Configuration Client NodeJS, Angular 2+, TypeScript, Protobuf, Pivotal Tracker

A distributed database product being developed required a tool so that nodes could be configured and monitored.

- · Worked on a 2 person team to develop the backend and frontend of a webapp
- Created components for manipulating nodes, clusters, and configuring machine learning algorithms to run across the clusters

Performance Monitoring Tool *C++*, *Protobuf, NCurses*

The database engine development team didn't have insight into where performance bottlenecks were. They had instrumented performance counters in the engine, but had no way to visualize the data.

- Implemented a TUI utility using C++ and NCurses to visualize performance counter data, or emit CSV for further analysis
- Backend team was able to use the utility to assess the effects of their changes on the performance of the system

Software Engineer (Co-Op) *MedPoint Digital*

Jan 2018 - May 2018

JWT Security and Performance Audit C#, .NET, JWT, Javascript

A set of APIs initially built without any security measures were being retrofitted with a JWT-based scheme to provide authorization for a distributed monolith.

- Discovered that the initial solution was not secure and far less performant than possible
- Wrote documents detailing how to exploit the vulnerability, and how to secure against the
- Proposed authorization solution would utilize database utilization more than 13 times less frequently

Uptime Monitoring Tool C#, .NET Core, Angular 2+, Typescript

Various services for a product had poor reliability and poor visibility for determining when they were unavailable, or if they had been down in the recent past.

- Wrote an internal tool that would record the recent uptime for the company's services and display them in a webapp.
- Webapp would display history for 3 days for service availability for services running on dev, test, and production environments

PROFESSIONAL EXPERIENCE

Rowing Instructor Taught sculling to rowing novices of all ages as a Summer job.

2012 - 2018

RIT Men's Crew Rowed and Coxed for RIT's 2nd Varsity 8.

2014 - 2017